{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Concentration polarization can be reduced further by", "opta": "pre filtering the solution", "optb": "reducing the flow rate per unit membrane surface area", "optc": "back washing periodically", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A system which require less solvent and produces a more concentrated extract phase, is desired with a", "opta": "large distribution coefficients", "optb": "small distribution coefficients", "optc": "very small distribution coefficients", "optd": "constant distribution coefficients", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The efficiency of cell disruption in a bead mill depends on the", "opta": "concentration of the cells", "optb": "amount and size of beads", "optc": "type and rotational speed of agitation", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A common filter medium is the cloth filter generally made of", "opta": "canvas", "optb": "synthetic fabrics", "optc": "metal or glass fiber", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An ion exchange resin is composed of", "opta": "polymeric network", "optb": "ionic functional groups", "optc": "counter ions", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Maintenance cost varies from", "opta": "0-4% of the capital cost", "optb": "12-16% of the capital cost", "optc": "4-8% of the capital cost", "optd": "8-12% of the capital cost", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The optimum wet solid content for the cell suspension for a bead mill is typically somewhere between", "opta": "5-15% by volume", "optb": "15-30% by volume", "optc": "30-60% by volume", "optd": "60-90% by volume", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Assuming the laminar flow across the filter, the rate of filtration (dVf/dt) can be expressed as a function of pressure drop Dp by the modified D'Arcy's equation as (where A is the area of filtering surface, K is the D'Arcy's filter cake permeability and L is the thickness of the filter cake)", "opta": "(1/A) dVf/dt = \u0394p/\u03bc(L/K)", "optb": "dVf/dt = (1/A)\u0394p/\u03bc(L/K)", "optc": "(1/A) dVf/dt = \u0394p/\u03bc LK", "optd": "dVf/dt = (1/A)\u0394p/\u03bc LK", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Filtration leaf test results indicate that the filtration rate of a protein product is 100 dry lbs/(ft2 hr). What size production filter would be required to obtain 100 dry lbs of filter cake/hr?", "opta": "1.54 ft2", "optb": "3.08 ft2", "optc": "65 ft2", "optd": "65 lbs/ ft2.hr", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Selectivity can be expressed as", "opta": "ratio of the distribution coefficients in different solute", "optb": "mass fraction of the solute in the extract phase at equilibrium", "optc": "mass fraction of the solute in the raffinate phase", "optd": "ratio of the mass fraction of the solute in the extract phase to the raffinate phase", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The disk centrifuge is the type of centrifuge used most often for bio separations due to its", "opta": "continuous operation", "optb": "lesser cost", "optc": "higher speed", "optd": "ease in operation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The effectiveness of a solvent can be measured by the", "opta": "distribution coefficients", "optb": "selectivity", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "diffusivity", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The stage wise operation of adsorption is called", "opta": "contact filtration", "optb": "conventional adsorption", "optc": "affinity adsorption", "optd": "ion exchange", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not the physical method for the cells rupturing?", "opta": "Milling", "optb": "Homogenization", "optc": "Ultrasonication", "optd": "Enzymatic digestion", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Conventional adsorption is a", "opta": "reversible process", "optb": "irreversible process", "optc": "either reversible or irreversible", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the solute passes through membrane freely, the the rejection coefficient (s) is", "opta": "1", "optb": "0", "optc": ">1", "optd": "<1", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the membrane rejects all solute, the rejection coefficient (s) is", "opta": "1", "optb": "0", "optc": ">1", "optd": "<1", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In antibiotic manufacturing processes, the fermentation time ranges from", "opta": "2-3 weeks", "optb": "1-2 weeks", "optc": "4-5 weeks", "optd": "2-4 weeks", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The conventional filtration involves the separation of large particles generally", "opta": "dp>5\u03bcm", "optb": "dp>10\u03bcm", "optc": "dp>15\u03bcm", "optd": "dp>20\u03bcm", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the operation does not come under upstream processing?", "opta": "Media preparation", "optb": "Inoculum development", "optc": "Effluent treatment", "optd": "Storage of raw material", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For cost analysis in a fermentor system, the depreciation cost varies from", "opta": "5-6% of the capital cost", "optb": "6-7% of the capital cost", "optc": "6-10% of the capital cost", "optd": "8-10% of the capital cost", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Micro filtration refers to the separation of suspended material such as bacteria by using a membrane with spore sizes of", "opta": "0.02 to 10\u03bcm", "optb": "1-10A\u00b0", "optc": "20-30\u03bcm", "optd": "10-200A\u00b0", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Start up expenses in a fermentation industry varies from", "opta": "0-5% of the capital cost", "optb": "10-15% of the capital cost", "optc": "5-10% of the capital cost", "optd": "15-20% of the capital cost", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The solvent flux across the membrane can be expressed as (where A is the area, Lp is the membrane permeability, \u03c3 is the reflection point, \u0394p is applied pressure and \u0394\u03c0 is the osmotic pressure)", "opta": "J = Lp(\u0394p - \u03c3\u0394\u03c0)", "optb": "J/A = Lp(\u0394p - \u03c3\u0394\u03c0)", "optc": "J = Lp/\u03c3\u0394\u03c0", "optd": "J/A = Lp/\u0394p", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is considered as a pretreatment to the biological feeds?", "opta": "Heating to denature the proteins", "optb": "Addition of filter aids to increase the porosity", "optc": "Addition of electrolytes", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the extractions operation, the selectivity should be", "opta": "> 1", "optb": "< 1", "optc": "1", "optd": "zero", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The purity of a solute collected between two times t1 and t2 during chromatographic separation can be calculated as", "opta": "amount of solute eluted - amount of impurity eluted", "optb": "amount of solute eluted / amount of impurity eluted", "optc": "amount of solvent eluted + amount of impurity eluted", "optd": "amount of solvent eluted / amount of impurity eluted", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Chromatography is based on the", "opta": "different rate of movement of the solute in the column", "optb": "separation of one solute from other constituents by being captured on the adsorbent", "optc": "different rate of movement of the solvent in the column", "optd": "any of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The correlation often employed to correlate adsorption data for protein is (where Ymax is the maximum amount of solute adsorbed per mass of adsorbent, X is the mass fraction of solute in the diluent phase in solute-free basis, KL is a constant and Y is the equilibrium value of the mass of solute adsorbed per mass of adsorbent)", "opta": "Y = YmaxX/(KL+X)", "optb": "Y = Ymax/(KL+X)", "optc": "Y = YmaxX/KL", "optd": "Y = Ymax- X/ (KL+X)", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A typical tubular centrifuge has a bowl of 2 to 5 inch in diameter and 9 to 30 inch in height with a maximum rotating speed of", "opta": "15,000 to 50,000 rpm", "optb": "50,000 to 100,000 rpm", "optc": "100,000 to 150,000 rpm", "optd": "150,000 to 200,000 rpm", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}